<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Vegetable Garden Lite (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.VegetableGardenLite</packageId>
  <author>Owlchemist</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/VegetableGardenLite</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
    <li>1.4</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>dismarzero.VGP.VGPVegetableGarden</packageId>
      <displayName>VGP Vegetable Garden</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2007061826</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>dismarzero.VGP.VGPVegetableGarden</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://i.imgur.com/buuPQel.png[/img]
Update of Owlchemists mod
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1698026875

[img]https://i.imgur.com/pufA0kM.png[/img]

[table]
    [tr]
        [td][url=https://dsc.gg/mlie][img]https://i.imgur.com/zdzzBrc.png[/img][/url][/td]
        [td][url=https://github.com/emipa606/VegetableGardenLite][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url][/td]
    [/tr]
    [tr]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/WjDSfUn.png[/img][/td]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/Be8E2qJ.png[/img][/td]
    [/tr]
[/table]
	
[img]https://i.imgur.com/Z4GOv8H.png[/img]
The goal of this fan-made mod is to tighten the scope of the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=1185265132]Vegetable Garden[/url] mod. It removes some content to emphasize just the farming side of things, and dialing back anything to with cooking or lumber. It also tweaks the balance to try and prevent and deviation from vanilla difficulty curves.

[i]Note: I am not officially associated with the Vegetable Garden mod, and this is just a fan-made edit for it.[/i]

[h1]List of changes[/h1]
[list]
[*]Ironwood removed as I felt it fell outside the scope of the mod, and also didn't pair well with the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1322101066andsearchtext=snowy+trees]Snowy Trees[/url] mod.
[*]Bamboo related content was removed.
[*]Silage was given a heavy nerf. In vanilla, kibble provides a 20% gain of nutrients in - out. Silage was 3.5x beyond that, while also carrying the same market value. It is now a 30% improvement, making it a respectable upgrade over kibble if you have the resources for it.
[*]Bulk meals prep now has a flat 4x work multiplier over singles, removing the built-in efficiency gain. The reason why was because I felt this recipe was double-dipping in efficiency, as your pawns will already gain indirect efficiency due to 4x less hauling of ingredients involved. Aside from that I felt it impacted labor-related difficulty too much in a cheaty way.
[*]Bulk meals now also require +4 cooking skill over the single versions. I felt the inclusion of bulk meals basically made the single option pointless to even have in the game anymore. Bulk meal prep is now treated as a reward for increasing cooking competence.

[u]March 30, 2019[/u]
[*]Some of the raw food in VG had nutrient values of 0.06 and 0.08. These have been changed to 0.05 while the plant yields were increased to compensate, effectively keeping the nutrients-per-yield the same. The idea is to keep all raw food at a consistent 0.05 across the game for easier gameplay understanding. An as aside, VG also patched vanilla berries and agave from 0.05 to 0.08, effectively buffing them. This buff has been reversed. The mass per item was also adjusted to compensate.

[u]April 27th, 2019[/u]
[*]The mod was renamed to Vegetable Garden Lite with an emphasis of altering VG's mod to mostly just the farming-related stuff and less so cooking.
[*]Specialty meals do not have bulk recipes anymore, like tea, coffee, or packaged survival meals.
[*]Fruit drinks are no longer considered health food (as far as the hediff buffs) but rather a recreational drink. It's comparable to chocolate. It gives more nutrients and joy than it did before instead of giving the health buffs.
[*]Most of the patching code has been rewritten for better performance and future-proof reliability.
[*]Stew and stir fry were removed as they were considered inconsistent to how generic meals work and the hefty health benefits that they would provide.
[/list]

[h1]Compatibility[/h1]
[list]
[*]SeedsPlease: place this mod below it.
[*]Expanded Woodworking: you no longer need its Vegetable Garden patch (unless you use the VG extension packs which add even more trees).
[/list]

[img]https://i.imgur.com/PwoNOj4.png[/img]
[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] or the standalone [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2873415404]Uploader[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[*] Use [url=https://github.com/RimSort/RimSort/releases/latest]RimSort[/url] to sort your mods
[/list]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/changelog/2427695567][img]https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/emipa606/VegetableGardenLite?label=latest%20version&amp;style=plastic&amp;color=9f1111&amp;labelColor=black[/img][/url]</description>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">1.5.0</modVersion>
</ModMetaData>